地心游记
中文字幕翻译：梦海肥亮
30724623@qq.com
崔佛
Trevor!
麦斯
Max.
哇  哇
Whoa, whoa.
尽管威格拿被整个科学界嘲笑
Although Wegener was ridiculed by the scientific community...
但他最终还是证实了
...he was eventually found to be correct...
世界上存在一个叫做“泛大陆”的原始大陆
...in his theory of an original supercontinent called Pangaea.
好吧
Yeah. Okay.
啊  正点
Ah. Come to papa.
嘿  雷诺
Hey, Leonard.
嘿  老友
Hey, man.
老友  我估计你要伤心了          为什么？
-Dude, you ain't gonna be happy. -Why?
基森来了       原来如此
-It's Kitzens. -I see.
你好     崔佛  我最好的朋友
-Hello. -Trevor, there's my favorite colleague.
艾伦，你好吗？   我还不错
-How are you, Alan? -I'm good.
你的“泛大陆”课程上得怎样了？  很好
-How's that Con Drift class of yours going? -Fine.
那么少学生听课  看来挺受欢迎的嘛
Does it get echoey in there with so few students?
那么你来这是要做什么呢？我很忙的
So, what do you got on the books? I'm busy.
确实  我看到你确实很忙
No, no, I can see how busy you are.
所以我会尽快的
So I'll try to be as quick as possible here.
学校决定要撤掉你哥哥的实验室
The university is pulling the plug on your brother's lab.
撤掉？
Pulling the plug?
对  我们终于可以有足够的地方用了
Yeah, it's gonna finally give us all the storage space we need.
咱们开门见山吧  这里的设备
Let's get something straight here, this facility is dedicated...
会用来研究麦斯关于
预测火山裂缝的理论
...to the research of Maxwell Anderson's theories predicting the volcanic fissures...
关键是  他的这个理论还没被证实
Which have never been proven.
我是说  你那个去世的哥哥所留下的仪器
还有多少个是没有坏的？一个？两个？
I mean, how many of your late brother's sensors are even still active? One, two...?
是三个  以前可是有二十九个
-Three. -It used to be 29.
现在撤掉我们是很不明智的
This is the wrong time to shut us down.
我已经得到了玻利维亚的地震活动性数据
我监测到了蒙古那里有十三毫米的变动
I have got seismic activity in Bolivia. I got a 13 millimeter shift in Mongolia.
艾伦  你不能撤掉我们  留下我们的实验室
Alan, you can't shut us down. Keep the lab open.
这些是麦斯留下的全部遗产
麦斯去世已经十年了，崔佛
-It's all I've got left of Max. -It's been 10 years since Max, Trevor.
很抱歉  真的
I am sorry about all this. I really am.
崔佛  你在家吗？  我是伊丽莎白
Trevor, are you there? It's Elizabeth.
请接电话
Pick up, please.
好吧  呃  我们现在在95号路
准备去你那里
Okay. Well, uh, we are on the 95, and we're heading your way.
小贤，你要跟你崔叔叔打声招呼吗？
You wanna say hi to your Uncle Trevor, Sean?
不要
No.
只是打声招呼而已  糟糕
Just say hello.   -No.
我不想说  这次惨了
I don't want to. -Oh, no.
嘿，我是你嫂嫂
Hey, it's your sister-in-law again.
我只是想确定一下你什么时候在家
Just wanted to make sure what time you'd be home...
因为我们准备六点左右到你那儿
... because we'll be there around 6.
好吧，那就这么定了
Okay. Well, we'll be on my cell.
不是吧   小贤很期待见到你
-Oh, boy. -Sean's looking forward to seeing you.
对吧小贤？  才怪
-Right, Sean?  Negatory.
我有点担心，我们可能多走了一个红绿灯
I'm getting worried that we might've gotten our signals crossed.
请回我电话
Please call me.
我不在家，请留言
I'm not home. Leave me a message.
崔佛  我们正停在你家前面
Trevor, we're pulling up in front of your building.
崔佛  你在吗？
Trevor, you in there?
嗨
Hi.
嘿  你好啊
-Hey. -How are you, Elizabeth?
啊，还好你在     见到你真好
-Oh, you're home. -It's so good to see you.
我也觉得
You too.
我刚收到你的留言   嗯哼
-How are you? I just got your messages. -Uh-huh.
你忘了  对吧？   我没有啊
-You forgot, didn't you? -I didn't forget.
我怎么可能忘呢？
How could I forget?
你没有忘记？   我
-You didn't forget? -I...
好吧  我忘了  但是这并不代表
I forgot. It doesn't mean I haven't been...
我不想见我的侄子
...Iooking forward to time with my nephew.
从他九岁开始我就没见过他了吧？
I haven't seen him since he was 9?
是七岁   哇，呵呵
-Seven. -Wow. Ha-ha.
那他准备待多久？
So how long is he gonna be staying again?
十天   我们之前是这么说的吗？
-Ten days. -Is that what we said?
嘿  小贤  你好吗
Hey, Sean. How are you?
应该好
Looking good.
这个是GAME BOY吗？（一种很旧的游戏机）
这是PSP（最新的游戏机）
-Is that one of those Game Boys? -It's a PSP.
哇  小贤起来，跟你叔叔打声招呼
-Cool. -Sean, get up, say hi to your uncle.
“你叔叔”你好
Hi to your uncle.
上次见到你的时候  你只有这么高
Last time I saw you, you were about this high.
噢！呵呵    嗯，好吧
-Oh! Ha-ha. -Yeah, good one.
拿好了？ 你有我的电话号码
You got that? Okay, you've got all my numbers.
你的机票和护照都在你的包里
You've got your ticket and passport in your bag.
我会在渥太华接你
I will be there to pick you up in Ottawa.
到时候我们就会有一栋新房子，开始新的生活
And by then I'll have found us a house and we can start on this big new adventure.
很刺激对吧？  当然
-Pretty exciting stuff, huh? Yeah, it's great.
就像加拿大人一样  刺激――死了
We get to be Canadians. Thrilling, eh?
不必拘谨
Just let yourself in.
跟你待在一起对他很有益处   嗯
-It will be good for him, being with you. -Yeah.
估计对你也有好处
Who knows? Maybe it will be good for you too.
这个给你
This is for you.
什么东西？  是小贤的吗？
What...? Is this Sean's?
不，是麦斯的
No, it's Max's.
麦斯的？  对
-Max's? -Yeah.
嘿  咱们哥俩一起出去玩吧
So, hey, dude. This is gonna be fun.
一定会很有趣
A couple of dudes hanging out.
玩个五天  或者一个星期
Five days, maybe a week.
你懂的  去玩些纯爷们玩的东西
You know, doing dude stuff, what dudes do.
你喜欢棒球吗？你知道我们应该做什么吗？
You like baseball? You know what we should do?
我们应该去一个棒球场
We should go get in a batting cage.
好吧  听着  我不太喜欢你做的这些
Yeah, okay, listen. I don't like this any more than you do.
你只要继续买你的威士忌喝
As long as you keep stocked with Mountain Dew...
看你的电视剧  我们河水不犯井水
...and TiVo Family Guy, we'll get along fine.
好     哇
-Sure. -Oh, wow.
这些硬币收藏品很不错嘛  嗯
-That's an awesome coin collection. -Oh.
这些算是我养的小宠物吧
Well, kind of a pet project of mine.
呵呵  真幽默   过奖
-Yeah, it's really nifty. -Thanks.
你饿不？  我们可以点外卖
You hungry? We could order in, you know.
例如披萨  中国菜  泰国菜
Maybe some pizza, Chinese, Thai food?
之类的
Subs? Or something like that?
哇  那是什么
-Wow. -What's that?
这些是一个非常伟大的人的遗物
Well, it's a box of possessions of a really great guy.
你爸爸
Your dad.
他的旧棒球手套
His old ball glove.
我妈很少谈起他
Mom doesn't talk about him very much.
我向你保证
Well, you can take my word for it.
他是世间少有的
He was one of those few people...
超级杰出人物
...who are just exceptional at everything they do.
噢  你看  这个就是咱们老一辈的PSP
Ooh. You see this? This was your old man's PSP.
摇摇？  不要小看这个摇摇
-A yo-yo? -Don't be dissing the yo-yo.
这里面藏着物理学的奥妙  包括离心力
This is physics at work. You got your centrifugal force.
万有引力  势能
Your gravitational pull, you got your potential energy.
而且，你知道吗
And in ancient times, did you know...
在远古时代  这种东西是个捕猎工具
...that this was actually used as a hunting implement?
看好了
Watch.
让我试试    对，还是让你拿着比较好
-Hey, here, let me try. -Yeah, you should probably take it.
呃  这是什么东西
I have no idea what this is.
哇
Hello.
这是他最喜欢的书
This was his favorite book.
凡尔纳的《地心游记》
Jules Verne's A Journey to the Center of the Earth.
我曾经想在暑假的时候读一读这本书
You know, I think that was on my summer reading list once.
不过始终没有读  那太不应该了  这本书超好看的
-I never got to it. -That's too bad, it's a good read.
对于他来说  这不仅仅是一部科幻小说  更是他的灵感来源
To him, it wasn't just science fiction, it was inspiration.
在我很小很小的时候  他曾经给我念过这本书
He used to read this to me when I was a really little kid.
哇，这些笔记是什么情况？
Hello. What are these notes?
蒙古的岩浆温度达到了一千一百五十？
"Magma temperatures reach 1150 in Mongolia"?
玻利维亚
"Bolivia."
夏威夷
"Hawaii."
小心！
Look out!
小贤  咱们去我的实验室看看
Hey, Sean, let's go check out my lab.
不能等明天再做吗？
So it couldn't wait for tomorrow?
你爸经常说
Your dad used to say:
地壳构造物理学是研究现状的科学
而不是用来研究未来的
"Tectonophysics is the science of now, not tomorrow."
它所研究的地质运动
是发生在电光石火之间的
It's about seismic events that occur in an instant.
看这里
Here, look at this.
夏威夷  玻利维亚  蒙古
You got Hawaii, Bolivia, Mongolia.
这些地方的现时数据 跟九七年七月的时候很相似
And the conditions today are almost exactly what they were in July '97.
九七年七月有什么特别吗？
What's the big deal about July '97?
小贤  那是你爸爸失踪的时间
Sean, that was the year that your dad went missing.
你看  这一纵列的数字
Now, look, you see this column of numbers here?
如果这个753  变成752的话  那么就说明……
If the 753, right here, was a 752, then it would be...
完全一致
Exactly the same.
这些信号是什么意思？
What do these little blips mean?
什么都别碰  这些信号是我毕生的心血
Don't touch anything. Those little blips are my life's work.
这四个信号点就是你的毕生心血？
These four little blips are your entire life's work?
三个  三个信号点
Three. Three little blips.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
冰岛
Iceland.
这就讲得通了
This makes sense.
麦斯在十年前看到了这些数据  然后他马上就去调查
Max saw the readings 10 years ago, and he took off to investigate.
如果现在的数据和当时是一致的话
Now, if the readings are the same today as they were then...
那么这就是我弄清楚一切的唯一机会
...this may be my only chance to find out what happened.
准备好你的护照  干嘛呢？
-I'm gonna need your passport. -For what?
不好意思  我必须提早带你去加拿大
I'm sorry, I have to get you to Canada a little earlier than we planned.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
我在说这个  《地心游记》
I'm talking about this. A Journey to the Center of the Earth.
一切答案都在冰岛  他一定就是在那里失踪的
It's all set in Iceland, which is where he must've gone.
这些全是我爸的笔记？
These are all my dad's notes?
听着
Look...
麦斯和我
...Max and l...
你爸爸和我认为  世上有可能存在一条火山通道
Your dad and I were talking about the possibility of volcanic tubes existing...
能够穿过地幔  直达地球的核心
...that went down past the mantle, towards the center of the Earth.
我想这就是他一直在找的答案
And that's what I think he went looking for.
对不起  明早我必须带你去渥太华
Sorry, I gotta put you on a flight to Ottawa in the morning.
而我则要去冰岛  不 不，听着
-And I'm calling Icelandair. -No, no, look.
嘿  我才刚到这里啊
-Hey. -I just got here, okay?
不要指望你能一走了之
You're not gonna go and ditch me.
况且是我发现你的毕生心血多了一个信号点的
I was the person who found your life's work fourth little blip thingy in the first place.
这是我们兄弟之间的事情  他是我爸
-This is my brother we're talking about. -It's my dad.
我不会去渥太华待十天的  我要跟你去
Now, I don't have to be in Ottawa for 10 days. I'm going with you.
你知道到雷克雅末克（冰岛首都）的机票有多贵吗？
Know how much to book a last-minute flight to Reykjavik?
我觉得你付得起
Something tells me you got it covered.
下来吧  勇敢的旅行者  进去马嚼子雪山的山口
"Descend, bold traveler, into the crater of the jokul of Sneffels...
入口就在斯嘉泰力山峰的阴影之下
..which the shadow of Scartaris touches before the kalends of July...
然后你就会到达地心
...and you will attain the center of the Earth."
呜
Ooh.
见笑了
Sorry.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我正在破解你爸爸留在书上的这些笔记
I'm deciphering these notations that your father made in this book.
我觉得答案就藏在这些字母之中
I think there's a code behind the pairing of letters.
可能跟元素周期表有关
It might have something to do with the periodic table.
例如  这里的S-A  L-S  G-G
For instance, I've got S-A, l-S, G-G.
我相信这个P-B就代表了元素周期表中的plumbum元素
I believe that P-B is on the periodic table and that's plumbum.
也就是“铅”  那“斯邦 格森”是什么意思
-Plumbum means lead. -What's "Sigurbjorn Asgeirsson"?
什么？
What?
看  这里  竖着读  “斯邦 格森”
Well, it's right here. Read it down. Sigurbjorn Asgeirsson.
噢  呃
Oh. Uh...
斯邦 格森  那就是
Sigurbjorn Asgeirsson, that's...
这是一个线索  可能是指某个地方
That's a clue. Maybe that's a place.
也可能是某种东西
It could be a thing.
你在干嘛？  我在百度
-What are you doing? -I am Googling at 30,000 feet.
这样做有用吗？   欢迎来到二十一世纪
-Are you supposed to be doing that? -Welcome to the 21 st century.
好了  看   这是一个人名
-Okay. Here. -It's a person.
斯邦・格森  他是格森协会的常务董事
"Sigurbjorn Asgeirsson, executive director...
这个协会主要研究火山进化学
...of Asgeirsson Institute for Progressive Volcanology."
麦斯可能认识这个人
Max would've known this guy.
我就知道带上你是明智选择  这个协会就是我们的第一站
I knew it was a good thing to bring you. His institute has gotta be our first stop.
我们到了吗？
Are we there yet?
不要着急
If you mean annoying, yeah, we're there.
是你开得太慢了  我这叫安全第一
-You know, you're going kind of slow. -I'm going kind of safe.
我刚看见一只山羊走在临时车道上
I just saw a goat in the passing lane.
我们的冒险什么时候才能开始？
When's the whole adventure thing gonna begin?
我给点有趣的事情让你做吧
Let me give you something fun to do.
人肉导航
Navigate.
我们在哪？
Where are we?
我们到了哈赞斯林没？
Have we passed Havanschlicht?
哈赞斯林？  对
-Havanschlicht? -Yeah.
不知道
I don't know.
我们到了英格斯塔没？
Have we passed Eingarsstadir?
不知道  雷林费呢？
-I don't know. -Reynivir?
不知道  胡撒维克？
-I don't know. -Husavik?
不知道  刚德宏？
No.  Grundarhol?
不知道  斯提塔德？
No.  Stifflarschtarder?
斯提塔德什么东西？
Stifflardschtarder?
那昆都卡塔斯金路奎呢？  纳尼？
How about Koldukardarskinoquue? What?
我们绝对是迷路了  没有啊
We're definitely lost. We're not lost.
看看有没有类似协会的建筑物吧
Just look for an institution.
一个协会机构一般是什么样的？  我不知道  应该是像一个协会那样的
What's an institution look like? -I don't know, it looks big and institutional.
应该是在这附近的了
It's gotta be around here somewhere.
看  那里有间房子  我们可以去那里问问人
Hey, look, there's a little shack up there. We can stop there and ask for directions.
我们没有迷路啊  好吧  你说没就没
-We're not lost. -Oh, no, definitely not.
这是什么？ 滑雪棚？
What's this? A ski shack?
格森协会
"Asgeirsson...
火山进化学
...Institute for Progressive Volcanology."
我就说我找到了嘛
I told you I'd find it.
好吧
Alrighty.
精神一点  好
-Not too shabby. -All right.
不好意思  我不懂冰岛语
Oh, I'm sorry, I don't speak Icelandic.
你好，什么事呢？  你好
-Hi, can I help you? -Hello.
我叫汉娜  啊，你好啊
-I'm Hannah. -Oh, how do you do? Hi.
我叫崔  安德森教授  是从美国过来的  呃
I'm Trev... Professor Anderson. I'm visiting from America. Um...
这是我的侄子  小贤  我是小贤
-This is Sean, my nephew. -I'm Sean.
你好
Hi, Sean.
不好意思打扰了  我想找
I was wondering if I could possibly speak with, forgive me here...
斯邦・格森先生
...Sigurbjorn Asgeirsson?
嗯
Um...
斯邦・格森已经死了
Well, Sigurbjorn Asgeirsson is dead.
死了？  对  三年前就死了
-Dead? -Yeah, he died three winters ago.
噢  呃
Oh. Uh...
那你是协会的成员吗？
So do you run the institute?
不是  这里没有什么协会
Nobody does. There is no institute.
可是下面那块牌子写着  火山进化学是一个荒谬的理论
-There's a sign down the road that says... -Progressive volcanology was a failed idea.
就像是  柏林墙和八轨磁带
Like, you know, the Berlin Wall and eight-track tapes.
懂了
I see.
那  你是他同事吗？
Well, did you work with him?
不 不  他是我父亲
No, no. He was my father.
嗯？这本书怎么了？
Yeah? I know it. What about it?
这本书是我死去的哥哥 麦斯的
Well, this book belonged to my late brother, Max.
麦斯・安德森
Max Anderson?
我相信他曾经跟你父亲联系过
We believe that he may have been in contact with your father.
你哥哥是个“凡尔纳教徒”吗？  什么意思？
-Your brother was a Vernian. -What's a Vernian?
就是指那些  觉得凡尔纳写的小说  是真有其事的人
Someone that believes that the writings of Jules Verne were actual fact.
我是说  这个人只是一个科幻小说作家
I mean, the guy was a science fiction writer.
但是这群“凡尔纳教徒”却将他当作神
And yet this society of believers regarded Verne like a visionary.
我父亲就是最狂热的教徒
My father was the biggest Vernian of them all.
我哥哥不是什么异教徒
My brother was no Vernian.
这是我父亲的资料
This was my father's copy.
看一下
Take a look.
看见了吗  这些记号完全一致  你哥哥就是个“凡尔纳教徒”
See, the markings are exactly the same. Your brother was a Vernian.
原来我爸爸是这样的人
Wow, my dad was kind of out there.
你不了解他  小贤  我怀疑你也不了解
-You didn't know him, Sean. -I'm starting to think you didn't either.
他不是什么神秘社团的成员
He was no member of some secret society.
你们来这要做什么？  我是个科学家  是个教授
-What are you guys doing here? -I'm a scientist, I'm a professor.
我来这里是因为  我的地震仪器监测到
I'm here because there are seismic sensors going off 30 klicks north of here...
这里以北三十公里的地方有异样
...that we think that we should check into.
这就是我们来这的原因  很单纯
And that's the reason that we're here, plain and simple.
好吧
Okay.
可是没有公路能够去北方
You know, there are no roads to the north.
呃
Well...
我是个登山向导  我可以带你去
I'm a mountain guide. I can take you there, professor.
好  太好了  我喜欢远足
-Great. -That's great, I love hiking.
太感谢你了  好
-I would appreciate that. That'd be great. -Good.
叫我崔佛就好了  叫我小贤
-Call me Trevor. -You can call me Sean.
去那里要五千块钱
So it will be 5000 kronur to go up there.
五千块一天吗？  没问题啊
Five grand a day? No problem.
一个小时
An hour.
一大堆硬币你收吗？
Do you accept rolls of quarters?
快点吧  我想在日落前回家
Come on, boys. I wanna be home by sundown.
嘿  你可以走慢一点吗？
Hey, you think you can slow down a little bit, please?
勃起了  什么？
-Dibs. -What?
我看着登山向导勃起了
I got dibs on the mountain guide.
你才十三岁  当我没说
-You're 13. -Sorry, called it.
才十三岁怎么会勃起呢  当我没说
-Thirteen-year-olds don't get dibs. -Get over it.
我们快要到了
We're getting closer.
好了  小心脚下的路  马嚼子山可是非常崎岖的
All right, just watch your step there. Mount Sneffels is deceptively treacherous.
什么是马嚼子？  不如让教授你来告诉他吧
-What's Sneffels? -Well, why don't you tell him, professor?
马嚼子山就是地心通道的
Sneffels is the name of the mountain where this character Liedenbrock...
地面入口
...apparently found a portal to the center of the Earth.
我们快去找到你的地震仪器吧
Let's just find that sensor of yours, professor.
就在那里
There it is.
太好了
Yes.
接下来你要怎么做呢？
Well, what do you need to do with it?
我要解下它  它就像一个装满了
I gotta unlock it. It's got, like, a black box...
过去十年所有地震活动性数据
...that has recorded all of the seismic activity...
的保险箱
...that's transpired in the last 10 years.
能让我得到很多关于麦斯的信息
Could tell me a lot about Max.
甚至能知道他失踪之前在做什么
And what he was doing when he went missing.
崔佛  打扰一下  我觉得我们必须离开
Trevor, I'm really sorry, we're gonna have to go now.
这仪器一定是被腐蚀生锈了
Must be corroded.
崔佛  我们要   哇
Trevor, we need to... Whoa.
好吧  我们要找个掩护物    快来 小贤
Okay, we need to take cover. Come on, Sean. Right now.
我随后就到
I'll be right there.
崔佛  暂时别管它了  我快要好了
-Trevor, just leave it for now. I've almost got it.
我们必须躲起来
We need to take cover now.
快过来  崔佛
Come on. Trevor.
崔佛叔叔  进来这里
-Uncle Trevor. -Get in here.
噢耶！  小心
-Yes. Oh!  Watch out.
赶紧  快点
Hurry up. Come on.
崔佛  那个仪器会把闪电引过来的
Trevor, the sensor's attracting the lightning.
扔了它  扔了那个仪器   你说什么！我才不会扔
-Drop it. Drop the sensor. What? I'm not gonna drop it.
赶紧！ 它把闪电都引过来了！
Hurry!  It's attracting the lightning!
崔佛？
Trevor?
崔佛？  我没事
-Trevor? I'm all right.
小贤？
Sean?
小贤你没事吧？  我没事
-Sean, you all right? -I'm good.
好  大家要保持冷静  快过来帮我挖开它
-Okay, everybody, just stay calm.  Guys, come on, you gotta help me dig.
快来
Come on.
算了吧  行不通的    算了？
-Forget it, it's no use. -Forget it?
她说得对
She's right.
我们头上起码压着六七十吨的巨石
There must be about 60 or 70 tons of boulders on top of us.
起码要挖一个月才能挖开
Take us about a month to dig out of here.
我们只能找别的出口  如果没有其他出口呢？
-We have to find another way. -What if there is no other way?
小贤  天无绝人之路
There's always another way, Sean.
你还有什么？
What else have you got?
照明弹  急救包  绳子  毯子  以及一些蛋白棒
Signal flares, first aid, some rope, blankets and a couple of protein bars.
但是这些不够我们吃的
But they're on a ration.
不知道我们要困在这里多久  困？这就是我们的处境？
-Don't know how long we'll be trapped for. -Trapped? Is that what we are?
她  她不是这个意思
She... No, she didn't mean that.
小贤你在干嘛？  可恶  这里不在服务区内
-Sean, hey, what are you doing? -God, I'm not getting any service.
在这下面你是收不到信号的  小贤
Sean, you're not gonna get any signal down here, okay?
收起来 好吗  不要太担心了
Put this away. Okay, don't worry about it.
我们一定会找到路的  好吧
-We'll find another way out, all right?  Okay.
其中一条路应该能回到地面的
One of these might snake back to the surface.
我们怎么知道要走哪条
How do we know which one to take?
我的直觉告诉我走右边这条
My gut says we go right.
来吧
Come on.
看来应该没错
Looks promising.
慢慢来  我们马上就能离开这里了
Just put one foot in front of the other. We'll be out of here in no time.
一切顺利
Looking good.
不要担心  我的第六感很准的
Don't worry, direction is my sixth sense.
小贤  别分心  把它当做野外调查
Pay attention, Sean. It's just like doing field work.
我向来都很喜欢做野外调查
I used to love doing field work.
小心！  啊！
-Watch out. -Ah!
教授  你现在不是在实验室里研究石头
You're not studying rocks in a lab, professor.
现在是生死关头  明白  谢谢
-This is life or death here. -Yeah, thanks.
你欠我一个人情
You owe me one.
这上面写的是什么？
What does this say?
意思是“禁止入内”
That means keep out.
这是明智选择  不 不，这是个好消息
-Maybe that's decent advice. -No, no. This is great news.
这条路有可能通往一个老矿洞  然后我们就能找到出路了
This might lead us to an old mine shaft and that could be our way out.
你觉得这里有多深？  麻烦给我个照明弹
-How deep do you think it is? -Can you give me one of those flares?
谢谢  小贤  准备好你的手表
Thank you. Sean, look at your watch.
我会点着照明弹  然后扔下悬崖
I'm gonna light this and drop it over the edge...
然后你算一下它经过多少秒钟到达底部
...and I want you to tell me how many seconds pass before it stops.
好
Okay.
准备了  三  二
Here we go. Three, two...
啊！我勒个去！
Oh, God!
什么情况？
What?
那是什么？
What was that?
是镁矿
Yup, magnesium.
这些墙壁后面一定是条矿脉
Must run in veins all through these walls.
镁是一种易燃物  对吗，教授？
Magnesium is kind of flammable, isn't it, professor?
对  经常被用来制作照明弹  火药 和 火柴
Yeah, used in flares, used in gun powder, matchsticks.
那么看来在这里不适合用火药和照明弹
Right, well, maybe gun powders and flares aren't such a good idea down here.
谢谢
Thank you.
跟刚才说的方法一样
It's the same principle.
准备好了吗 小贤？  好  扔吧
-You ready, Sean?  Yeah, go ahead.
三  二
Three, two...
一秒
One.
两秒
Two.
差不多三秒
Almost three.
让我算一下  这里有二百英尺深
Thirty-two squared by... It's 200 feet.
那就没问题
That's no problem.
差不多是普通楼房的二十层高
It's about your basic 20-story high-rise.
你的绳子够长吗？  当然够
-You got enough rope? -I always have enough rope.
呃  你们在说什么？
Well, no problem for what?
用绳索吊下去
Rappelling down in there.
我们要下去这个又深又黑的大坑？！
We're gonna rappel down that deep, dark hole?
怎么？ 你有意见？
What, you got a problem with that?
呃  怎么了？
-Pfft. -What's the matter?
我绝对不要下去这里
There's no way we should be rappelling down.
你在说什么？ 你可是能够对着登山向导勃起的男子汉了
What are you talking about? You're man enough to call dibs on the guide.
但我不能用绳子爬下去  你们两个！
-But not enough to climb down a rope.  Guys.
勃起跟这个不一样  以后请不要再谈论这个话题
-Calling dibs on the mountain guide... -No one gets dibs on the mountain guide.
我们下去吧
We're going down there.
稳住  稳住
Steady, steady.
记住  我们是绑在一起的
Remember, we're all connected.
很好
It's okay.
一切顺利
Looking good.
我这边没问题
It's all good down here.
慢慢放
Way down here.
你们会下来的 对吧？
You guys are coming down, right?
到你了 小贤  我会慢慢地把你放下去的
All right, Sean, I'm gonna start lowering you down really, really slowly.
你只要身体后仰  双腿高于身体那就可以了
So just lean back and keep your feet up high.
你行的
You're okay, Sean.
我们是用绳子连在一起的  所以不会有危险的
We're tethered together, so nothing bad is gonna happen.
对  当然
Yeah, sure.
很好
Good.
小贤  向下走
Sean, keep walking.
你必须迈出脚步
You have to keep walking.
好
Good.
嘿  你做得不错嘛
Hey, you're looking pretty good there.
一看就知道你以前没试过这样   闭嘴
-Sure you haven't done this before? -Shut up.
喂  麻烦你注意你的脚下
Hey, you mind? Watch your step, will you?
我现在可是拿命来玩
I'm hanging on for my life here.
小贤  跟我聊聊天放松一下吧
Okay, Sean, just make conversation with me.
呃  汉娜你经常来这里吗？
So, Hannah, do you come here often?
停一下
Oh, give me a break.
你的话题也太无聊了吧
That can't be the best line you can come up with.
我是在跟她聊天  不 小贤  我没有经常来这里
-I'm making conversation with her. -No, Sean, I do not come here very often.
准备好了？
Ready?
嘿
Hey.
看这些岩石
Look at all this schist.
怎么了？  是变质岩
-What? -It's a metamorphic rock.
绿片岩  石榴石  云母
Green schist, garnet schist, mica-garnet schist.
好吧  片岩    你看  到处都是  我估计
-Oh. Schist. -It's everywhere, look at it. I guess...
崔佛
Trevor.
抓住墙壁    我抓不到
Get to the wall, Trevor.  I can't.
我离墙壁太远了    你的绳子拉住了我的
-I can't, the walls widen out down here. -Your rope is caught on mine.
你会把我们都拉下去的  我必须割断你的绳索
You're gonna take us down. I gotta cut you loose.
什么？  不要啊汉娜
What? -Hannah, no.
等一下啊 喂
Wait a minute, wait, wait, wait.
别 别 别
-Don't. Don't, don't, don't.
崔佛叔叔  啊！
-Uncle Trevor. -Ah!
各位  到了
Hey, guys, found it.
这里就是底了
The bottom's right here.
汉娜  你知道我摔不死的对吧？
Hey, Hannah, you knew that, right?
对吧？
Right?
汉娜？
Hannah?
这是什么？
Guys, what's this?
我觉得是一个废弃矿坑
Looks like an abandoned mine tunnel to me.
这是奥布拉格矿坑
That's Old Bla'gils Mine.
自从六十年前那场大灾难之后  它就被封闭了
It was shut down 60 years ago after the big disaster.
灾难？
Disaster?
多大？
How big?
死了八十一个人
Eighty-one dead.
确实是大灾难
That's pretty big.
来吧
Come on.
走
Cowboy up.
崔佛  那本书上有提到这么个矿坑吗？
Hey, Trevor, was there a mine like this in the book?
应该没有
No, don't think so.
汉娜？  怎么了？
-Hannah? Yup?
我能问你个问题吗？
Can I ask you something?
你觉得  你父亲和我哥哥的观点  有没有可能是正确的呢？
Do you wonder if your father and my brother weren't wrong?
我明确地告诉你
Let me make something very clear to you.
我跟我父亲不同
I am not my father.
他的观点跟我一点关系都没有
And the world that he belonged to has nothing to do with me.
懂了  好的
I understand, of course.
我只是问一下
I didn't mean to say that it was or that it would be...
你知道我一直在计时的吧？  你还在算我的钱？
-You know I'm still on the clock, right? -You're still billing me?
一直算到我平安回到家
I bill you until I'm safe in my house.
呵  汉娜
-Huh.  Hannah?
这是什么？
What's that?
这是一台老式发电机  嘿  别乱碰
-This is the old generator for the mine. -Hey, you don't want to touch that.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
那台旧机器估计很不稳定的
There might be some volatile compounds there, you know.
确实很不稳定     汉娜  它有可能会爆炸
-Serious generator. Hannah, that thing could blow up.
不要拉下开关
Stop throwing switches.
等一下  别啊
Don't do that. No, wait.
别碰那个东西
Get away from that thing.
好吧  当我没说过
Okay, I take it back.
这里会有出口对吧？  那些矿工总得把挖到的东西运出去
This is it, right? I mean, the miners, they had to get their stuff out somewhere.
对  这些轨道可以通到外面
Yeah.  These tracks could lead us out.
汉娜  有多少矿工逃过那场灾难？
Hey, Hannah, how many miners got out?
一个
One.
那就代表有希望  我打前锋
That's a start. I call front.
什么？ 别 别 别
What? No, no, no.
不要进去那里
Come on, don't get in there.
我们不知道这些东西有没有坏
We don't even know if these things work.
这样很不安全
They're not safe.
这些轨道也未必安全
The tracks might not be safe.
引擎看起来没问题  进来
Track ahead looks good. Get in.
小贤  你这样很危险  是我就不会那样做了
Hey, Sean, it doesn't look safe. I wouldn't do that.
我好像看见了什么  那是……
I think I see something. It's...
那是阳光吗  不是的话就不用告诉我了
Please tell me it's daylight. Otherwise, I don't wanna know.
呃
Uh...
不  那不是阳光
No, it's not daylight.
噢  我们要掉下去了
Oh, we're in deep schist.
真希望这辆车里面有安全带
I wish there were seat belts on this thing.
你还担心这种无聊的事情？
You're worried about seat belts?
哇！ 啊！
-Whoa!  Ah!
小心
Watch it.
汉娜  我看到
-Hannah. -I know.
刹车 快刹车   不 别
-Pull the brake, pull the brake. -No, don't.
我们来不及刹车的
We won't make it.
耶
Yeah.
做得好  谢了
Hey, great job. Thanks.
糟了  小贤 坐稳了
Guys. Stay put, Sean.
你没事吧 崔佛
Trevor, you okay?
汉娜 你的轨道没路了
Hannah, your track ends.
跳过来我这
Jump in my car.
什么？
What?
快  你必须跳过来
Quick, you have to do it.
快跳  我知道
-Just jump. -I know that.
准备  啊！
Ready? Ah!
崔佛  你的轨道也没路了
Trevor, your track ends too.
好吧  你在做什么？
-Okay. -What are you doing?
我在拯救咱们的性命  来
Showing the proper way to save someone's life. Come on.
需要我帮忙吗？  好了
-Can I help? -Okay.
准备
Ready?
你没事吧？  没事
-Are you all right? -Yeah.
幸好有个垫子
Luckily, I had a soft landing.
现在你欠我两个人情了
That's two you owe me now.
谁会去数这些啊？  我会
-Who's keeping count? -I am.
刺激死了
That was awesome.
你们怎么了？  别提了
-What happened to you guys? -Don't ask.
那是什么？
What's that?
你要去哪？  别进去
Where are you going? Don't go in there.
你说什么呢？ 这可能是条出路
What are you guys talking about? This could be our way out.
墙上开了个洞
There's a hole in the wall.
大家看
Guys, check it out.
红宝石
Rubies.
翡翠
Emeralds.
月长石
Feldspar.
呃  各位 这里还有很多
Uh, guys, there's more.
钻石
Diamonds.
爽爆了
Bling.
矿石结晶通常都是形成在
Crystals are frequently formed and found...
火山通道里面
...in volcanic tubes.
这条通道能引导我们回去 对吗？
This tube could take us back up, right?
嗯哼  我们离地面不远了吧
-Uh-huh. -We're not far from the surface.
嗯哼  出去之后我要买一辆玛莎拉蒂汽车
-Uh-uh. -When we get out, I'm getting a Maserati.
钱不是唯一重要的东西  小贤  还有其他同样重要的东西 性命
Money is not the only thing that matters, Sean. People matter too, you know.
还有诸如此类的    如果你能拥有一辆玛莎拉蒂就不会这么说了
-Something like that.  Not if you have a Maserati.
你们听到了吗？
Did you guys hear that?
都别动
Nobody move.
不要被我猜中了
Tell me that's not what I think it is.
白云母
Muscovite.
什么是白云母？
What's muscovite?
白云母是一种很薄的岩石  有多薄
-Muscovite is a thin type of rock formation. -How thin?
呃  薄到只要重量和压力发生一丝一毫的改变
Well, so thin that the slightest change in weight and pressure...
都会使它崩塌
...can cause it to shatter.
我们正站在一大堆白云母上面
And we're standing on a lot of it.
停  停
Just stop. Stop.
好  它们稳住了
Okay, they're stopped.
你要完全按照来时的路走回去
I need you to walk back exactly the way we came from.
要非常非常平稳 懂吗？
Very, very calmly, okay?
轻轻地走
Tread lightly.
慢慢来  很好
Heel, toe. Doing good.
很好  要非常慢
Doing great. Very slowly.
好  继续
Good. Come on.
就是这样
That's it.
做得好
That's great.
要非常小心  继续走
-Really careful. -Keep going.
不
No!
它比我想象的要厚一些
It's actually thicker than I thought.
我们还在往下掉！
We're still falling!
崔佛  书上是怎么说的？
Trevor, what's at the bottom?
呃  如果凡尔纳写的是真的话
Well, if what Verne wrote was right...
这些通道有成百上千公里的深度
...these tunnels could go for hundreds, thousands of miles.
凡尔纳写的是小说
Verne was not right.
崔佛继续说  书上还说了什么？
Trevor, finish. What's at the bottom?
然后就没有然后了
Most likely theory is that it just ends.
没了？  有没有其他可能性？
Ends? Got any other theories?
通道的墙壁有可能被
Well, the walls of this tunnel could have gently eroded...
经过其表面的水所侵蚀
...by water which still runs through it...
这些水可以缓冲我们的下坠
...providing a gradual break to our fall.
有点像一条水滑道  水滑道
-Kind of like a water slide. -Water slide.
好  这个可能性我喜欢
Okay, that's a theory.
但是这些水有没有可能形成石笋刺穿我们？
But wouldn't the water have formed stalagmites pointing straight up at us?
我们会变成人肉串   那也是一种可能性
-We'll be skewered. -That is also possible.
这是水吗？
Is that water?
对 是水
Yes. Water.
水滑道  水滑道
Water slide, water slide.
它要来了  稳住
Here it comes. Hang on.
小贤！小贤！
Sean! Sean!
小贤  你没事吧？
Sean, Sean, you all right?
我们没有变成人肉串
We didn't get skewered.
游到岩石上
Make for the rocks.
汉娜呢？
Where's Hannah?
汉娜！汉娜！
Hannah! Hannah!
我的背包太重了
My backpack was too heavy.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在的比分是多少了？
So where does that put us now?
相差一分
Back to one.
我们在哪？
Guys, where are we?
那些是星星吗？
Are those stars?
不
No.
那只是山洞的顶部
That's just the ceiling of the cave.
是我眼花呢  还是说那个顶部
Is it just me, or is the cave ceiling...
在动？
...moving?
对
Yeah.
好像确实在动
It does look like it...
对吧
...doesn't it?
是小鸟
They're birds.
电子雀？
Electric birds?
它们好像是荧光鸟
They look like Cyanis rosopteryx.
只有它们能够进行生物发光  就像是萤火虫
Only they're bioluminescent, like fireflies or glowworms.
真是难以置信
It's incredible.
帅
Cool.
荧光的……鸟
Glow... birds.
你以前见到过这些生物吗？
Have you seen these creatures before?
在博物馆见过  但那些都是化石
Yeah, in the museum, but they were fossilized.
这些生物在一千五百万年前就灭绝了
These things have been extinct for over 150 million years.
它们去哪？  嘿  有条通道
Where are they going? Hey, a tunnel.
大家快来
Guys, come on.
小贤  等我一下
Sean, wait. Wait for me.
各位尊贵的来宾  欢迎来到地球核心
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you the center of the Earth.
麦斯是对的
Max was right.
他说的没错
He was right.
麦斯是对的！
Max was right!
你爸爸是对的
Your dad was right.
他是对的
He was right.
汉娜 你父亲也是对的
Hannah, your dad was right too.
即使别人都跟他们说
They both believed...
这是不可能的  但他们仍然坚信自己的观点
...in something that everyone told them was impossible.
他是对的
He was right.
那上边的光球是什么？  我不知道
-What's that light up there? I can't tell.
可能是一种能自行发光的气团
It must be some sort of luminescent gas combination.
我不确定
I don't know.
有点像一个容器
It's like a terrarium.
一个埋在地壳底下数千公里的容器
A terrarium thousands of miles beneath the crust of the Earth.
一个小世界
A world within the world.
水花的声音从老远就能听到
"The waterfalls, which for a long time, could be heard flowing from afar...
古老的瀑布沿着峡谷的峭壁
...now cascaded along the towering canyon walls...
永不止息地流淌
...streaming along the rock with no end."
这跟书里面莱登伯格所描述的一样
I mean, it's the same thing Liedenbrock wrote.
你是说  莱登伯格这个小说人物是真有其人？
Are we saying that Liedenbrock the character was real?
他真的存在？
That he existed?
有人来到这里  然后发现了这一切
Someone came down here. Someone saw all this.
然后出去了  最后告诉给凡尔纳
Someone got out and someone told Verne.
有人出去了？
Somebody got out?
这是我今天听过最爽的话
That's the best thing I've heard all day.
难道这一切没有让你大开眼界吗？
Doesn't this just completely blow your mind?
确实是大开眼界
My mind is blown, yes.
巨型石化蘑菇
Enormous fossilized mushrooms.
像是一种极其巨大的真菌
Sort of like humongous fungus.
难道书里的一切都是真的？  很有可能
-Everything in the book is real? -Probably.
包括那些危险的情节？  我也在担心这个
-And the really dangerous parts? -I was thinking about that too.
好吧
Right.
崔佛 快来
Trevor, come quick.
小贤？  小贤？
-Sean? -Sean?
我要进去了    等 等一下
-I'm going in. -Yeah, wait up.
喂  别着急
Hey, slow down.
我等下再过去
I'll be right there.
好像有人住在这里？
Someone actually lived here?
这个人
That somebody...
就是莱登伯格
...was Liedenbrock.
看看他的这些工具
Look at all his gear.
这些工具的制作方法都是
All this, state of the art...
一个世纪前的工艺
...a century ago.
“麦斯”
崔佛
Hey, Trevor.
我想我找到了莱登伯格的笔记本
I think I found Liedenbrock's notebook.
看
Look.
上面画的好像是  在树林的另一边有一个地底湖
Looks like on the other side of those trees there's some sort of underground ocean.
对
Yeah.
但我觉得这不是莱登伯格的笔迹
I don't think that's Liedenbrock's handwriting.
是我爸的笔迹
It's my dad's.
崔佛？
Trevor?
我能跟你聊聊吗？
Can I talk to you for a minute?
到外面来
Out here.
你在这等我好吗？
Can you wait here for a minute?
我想我找到麦斯了
Hey, I think I found Max.
我从来没有机会去了解他
I never really got a chance to know him.
我真希望能有这么个机会
I mean, I wish I did.
他写了一段话  我想让你听听
He wrote something and I want you to hear it.
九七年 八月 十四日
"August 14, 1997.
今天是小贤的生日
Today was Sean's third birthday.
六个星期之前  我打算在这个时候
Six weeks ago, I promised myself I would be home in time...
送他一对棒球手套
...to give him his first baseball glove.
现在恐怕
Now I'm worried...
我已经没这样的机会了
...that I'll never get the chance.
我来这里是为了找到这个神奇的世界  将这个发现与崔佛以及全世界分享
I set out to make an incredible discovery to share with Trevor and the world.
但是现在  我愿意放弃这一切
But now, I would trade it all...
我只想看着你长大
...just to be able to watch you grow up...
成为一个勇敢 有担当的男子汉
...to be the brave and caring man...
我相信你一定不会让我失望的
...I am certain you will become.
生日快乐  小贤
Happy birthday, Sean.
我爱你
I love you.
爹爹
Daddy."
永别了  麦斯
Goodbye, Max.
别难过
Come on.
按照麦斯的笔记
According to Max's journal...
我们所处的这个地方被熔岩包围着
...we're here in this giant air pocket that's surrounded by lava.
每隔一段时间就有地震发生
And during periods of intense seismic activity...
就像现在这样  对
-Like the one we're in now. -That's right.
包围我们的岩浆
-The magma that surrounds us...
会慢慢地将这个地方变成一个巨型烤箱
...turns this place into pretty much just a big oven.
这就是我爸爸的遭遇吗？
Was that what happened to my dad?
听着  我知道我只是个孩子  但我能承受的了  相信我
Look, I know I'm just a kid, but I can handle this, really.
坐
Sit down.
麦斯设计了一个逃跑方案
Max was planning an escape.
他的笔记写道  这里的温度能轻易达到二百摄氏度
His notes say that temperatures down here can easily hit 200 degrees.
人类最多只能承受一百五十摄氏度
A human being can't survive beyond 135.
现在已经九十五度了  我们刚到这的时候是八十二度
-It's already 95 degrees. -It was 82 when we got here.
温度上升得很快  那我们怎么做？
-Temperature's rising quickly. -So, what do we do?
我认为我们要遵照麦斯的方案
I say that we follow Max's plan.
他是这样写的
Here's what he wrote:
根据凡尔纳的小说
"My analysis of the original Verne text...
我相信向北横渡整个地下海洋之后
...leads me to believe that across the ocean due north of my current position...
会找到一条类似喷泉的河流  它可以带我回到地面
...is a geyser-like river which could be used to return to the surface."
所以  我们要横渡这个地下海洋
So, what we have to do is get across this ocean...
然后找到那个喷泉  回到地面
...and find the geyser and just hitch a ride topside.
听起来不错
Topside sounds good.
实际操作起来会复杂一点
It's a little trickier than that.
如果温度太热的话  河流就会蒸发
It could get so hot that the water'll evaporate.
我们还有多少时间？
How much time do we have?
四十八小时  最多七十二小时
Forty-eight hours. Seventy-two, tops.
可能更少
Probably less.
好  那么现在的问题是
Okay, so the question is:
怎样才能以最快速度横渡海洋？
What is the fastest way to get across the ocean?
我们不可能从陆地绕过去  因为……
There's no way we can get around it, because if we hike...
对  我们不够时间
Oh, we don't have time.
我们没有时间这样做
There's no time to do that.
书上都写着
It's all in the book.
嘿  你还好吗？
Hey, you all right?
温度多少了？
What's the temperature doing?
已经一百度了
It is a hundred degrees.
小贤 把三叶虫吃掉  这样才有力气干活
Eat your trilobite, Sean. We gotta keep our strength up.
好孩子
Attaboy.
嘿
Hey.
我们需要一个中心船桅吗？
Don't we need a center mast?
不  不需要
No. We don't need it.
我们的风力在很高的地方
The wind that we want is way up there.
热气流   高处的气流比低处的要快得多
Thermal. It's a lot faster than what we got down here.
做得好  就这样做
Good job. That should just about do it.
嘿  有个好东西给你
Hey, I got something for you.
这是什么？  指南针
What is this?  It's a compass.
是你爸爸的
It was your dad's.
有一年圣诞节  你妈妈送给他的
I remember the Christmas that your mom gave it to him.
她希望你爸爸随时随地都能找到回家的路
She wanted to make sure that he could always find a way back home.
希望它能带你回到她的身边
And maybe it will help you find a way back to her.
谢谢 崔佛    应该的
-Thanks, Trevor. -You got it.
这对我意义深重   对我也是
-It means a lot to me. -Me too.
噢 还有一件事要告诉你    在这里  磁极是颠倒的
Oh, there's one thing you should know. Down here, the polarity is reversed.
北方其实是南方   南方其实是北方
I mean, north is south, south is north...
而我们需要向北穿过海洋
...and we need to bear due north across the sea.
你是说  向南
You mean, south.
聪明
Exactly.
好  我们把它拿起来吧
All right, it's starting to pick up now.
好  抓好了   稳稳地抓好了
Okay, hold it. Hold it really steady.
好  好  好
Good, good, good.
准备好了吗？  嗯
-Good. Ready?  Yeah.
三  二  一  放！
Three, two, one, go!
耶  好
-Yeah.  All right.
耶   好
Yeah. All right.
太好了
Yeah.
冲啊
Go, go, go.
爽  继续
Yeah. Keep going.
哇 我们启程了
Whoa, we're going, we're going.
喂  等等我啊
Hey, well, can you wait for me?
上来  快 快 快
Well, get on.  Come on, come on, let's go.
它又来了
He's back.
嘿  老友
Hey, little guy.
看见那些云了吗？
Seen those clouds?
嗯
Yeah.
现在我们刚好乘着水流的方向   可以放低一点帆布
The current's pulling us in the direction we wanna go. We should lower the kite.
不可以  现在已经一百零九度了
Can't do that. It's a hundred and nine degrees.
越来越热了
It's getting hotter.
我们要全速前进   不用放低
We need all the speed we can get. Leave it up.
不过是毛毛细雨
It's just a little storm.
没什么大不了
Ain't no big deal.
下面有东西在移动
Something moving down there.
有磷皮  会游泳
Phosphorous and plankton.
就是我们在沙滩上见到的那些生物
It's the same thing we saw back at the beach.
我不确定  有点像巨型浮游生物
I don't know. It looks kind of big for plankton.
小贤  这里不是海洋公园  不要探那么出
Sean, we're not at SeaWorld, so back off a little bit.
听到了吗？  好像是一种鱼
-All right? -I think it's some sort of fish.
别
No.
他们到处都是
They're everywhere.
小贤  我就说我们会去棒球场的
Sean, I told you we'd get to the batting cage.
干掉它们
Batter up.
好  看看你有什能耐
Okay. Let's see what you've got.
好  棒球直击
Yeah. Line drive.
你有听到声音吗？
-Sean! -Do you hear something?
喂？ 小贤
-Hello? Sean.
妈妈？  我们好久没联系了
-Mom? -I think we have a bad connection.
妈妈  我听不清楚
Mom, I can't hear you.
你在哪？
Where are you?
崔佛叔叔和我  呃
Uncle Trevor and I, uh...
我们估计是在钓鱼
...we're sort of on a fishing trip and...
玩得开心吗？
Are you having fun?
别  不准这样
Whoa, no, you don't.
崔佛叔叔刚钓到一条大的  小贤？
-Uncle Trevor just caught a really big one. -Sean?
我的手机  小贤  你能反手击球吗？
-My phone. -Sean, do you know how to switch hit?
就位？  好
-Ready?  Yeah.
全垒打
Out of the ball park.
小贤   小心
-Sean. -Look out.
让我来  让我来
I got it, I got it.
小贤  别 别
Sean.  No, no, don't.
不要靠近边缘
Get away from the sides.
看它们在做什么
Look what they're doing.
它们对我们没兴趣  它们只想吃鱼
They don't want us. They want the fish.
听好了小贤  你去控制方向  我们要改变航道
Listen up. Sean, you take the tiller, we'll get the line.
汉娜  抓住那条绳子
Hannah, hold the slack.
小贤  右满舵
Sean, you wanna take us hard starboard?
啥？
What?
这边
That way.
快
Come on.
好   做得好
-Okay.  Doing good.
慢慢离开它们  慢慢地
Now just let it out gently. Let it out gently.
慢慢驶过去
Let it out slowly.
成功了
It's working.
咱们摆脱它们了
We're pulling clear of them.
真有你的  崔佛叔叔
You're the man, Uncle Trev.
那当然  周围的人都这么说我
That's what I've been telling the scientific community for years.
汉娜
Hannah.
我看看
Let me see.
绳子
The lines.
抓到了  小贤
Got it.  Sean.
小贤  别那样  别
Sean, don't do that. No, Sean.
小贤
Sean!
不  小贤！  崔佛！
-No, Sean! -Trevor!
小贤！  坚持住！
-Sean!  Hang on!
别放手！
Don't let go!
不
No.
崔佛？
Trevor?
有人吗？
Hello?
嗨  老友 这是哪里？
Hey, little guy. Where are we?
你知道哪里能找到水吗？
Hey, do you know where I can get some water?
我居然跟鸟说话
I'm talking to a bird.
我一定是傻了
I must be losing it.
小贤！
Sean!
停
Wait.
风把他往这个方向吹
The wind blew him this way.
我们是在往北走吗？
We still heading north?
对  没错
Yeah, still north.
他很聪明  他知道要怎么做
He's a smart kid. He knows the plan.
我相信他会去那条河找我们的
I'm sure he'll be waiting by the river.
我们去找河吧
Let's find that river.
喂  等一下
Hey, come on, wait up.
你去哪了？
Where'd you go?
好样的
Good job.
好了
Okay.
现在怎么走？
Now which way?
南
South.
很好
That's good.
那条河在北方
The river's north.
好
Okay.
来  我来拿这个
Here, let me take that.
不用  我没事   来吧  让我来拿
-No, no, I'm fine. -Come on, let me take it.
崔佛  我没事    汉娜 汉娜  我来
-Trevor, I'm fine. -Hannah, Hannah, I got it.
我们休息一下吧
Let's just stop for a second.
我们一定会找到他的
Hey, we're gonna find him.
喝吧
Drink that.
就剩下这些水了？  对
-Is that the last of the water? -Yeah.
我们以后还要用  先留着吧
We're gonna need that. Keep it.
汉娜  喝吧
Hannah, drink it.
喝吧
Come on.
趴下！
Duck!
我勒个……  这是什么东西？
-What the...?  What was that?
大型肉食性植物？
Large carnivorous plant?
汉娜
Hannah.
汉娜？
Hannah?
汉娜
Hannah.
啊
Ugh.
坚持住
Hang in there.
这次我得一分  对吧？
That's one point for me, right?
对
Right.
谁会去数这些  对吧？
Who's keeping track, right?
我懂了
I get it.
这是一个磁场
It's a magnetic field.
不是吧
No way.
漂浮石？
Magnetic rocks?
别 别 别
No, no. No, no, no.
坑爹啊
No. No.
你不用翅膀来试试
You try that without wings.
就是那条河
That's the river.
喷泉一定在那个山洞里
Geyser must be inside that cave.
小贤！
Sean!
他在哪？
Where is he?
他 在 哪？
崔佛？
Trevor?
我真后悔没有读过那本书
Man, I really wish I'd read that book.
我看不到他
I don't see him anywhere.
崔佛？ 崔佛
Trevor? Trevor.
等一下   你想做什么？
Hang on a minute. What are you doing?
我要去找我的侄子
I'm going to get my nephew.
汉娜
Hannah.
一切都是我的错
This is all my fault.
你先逃吧
Save yourself.
回家去
Just go home.
我会在河那里等你
I'll wait for you at the river...
等到不能等为止
...for as long as I can.
你这是为什么？
What did you do that for?
以防万一
Just in case.
小贤！
Sean!
小贤？！
Sean?!
小贤！
Sean!
小贤！小贤！
Sean! Sean!
来！
Come on!
天啊   见到你真好
Oh, God, I'm glad to see you.
我也是
Yeah, you too.
没事吧？   嗯
-Are you all right? -Yeah.
快走
We should go.
等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
那里是喷泉吗？   对  是我们的目的地
-Is that the geyser? -Yeah, that's where we're going.
快
Come on.
你以前见过恐龙吗？   骨头就见过
-Haven't you ever seen a dinosaur before? -Not with skin on it.
它太快了   我们跑不过的
He's too fast. We're not gonna make it.
崔佛 你要做什么？   那里有白云母
-Trevor, what are you doing? -That's muscovite.
就是之前让我们掉下来的那种东西
Same thing that we fell through before.
不可以   那东西承受不了你
There's no way it's gonna hold you.
更承受不了它   你只管跑
It can't hold him either. Now you run.
崔佛 别
Trevor, no.
它们没有裂  崔佛
It's not breaking, Trevor.
继续跑！
Keep running!
它要追上你了   我知道
-He's gaining on you. -I know.
别停下
Keep going.
啊！哇
Ah! Whoa.
崔佛 开始裂了
Trevor, it's working.
小心！
Look out!
崔佛！
Trevor!
我想起来了   我最讨厌野外调查
I just remembered something. I hate field work.
崔佛  来
Trevor, come on.
这个……  你这次有点……
That was like... And then you were like...
我知道   这次真幸运
Yeah, I know. I'm really lucky.
好了  这边
Okay, that way.
好像不太好    那里更糟
That, no good. That, worse.
咱们走
Let's go.
是河   我们怎么去到喷泉那里？
The river. How are we gonna get to the geyser?
水在沸腾   我们需要能漂浮的东西
-Water's boiling. -We need something that floats.
随便都可以   我们可以找个木头或者
Anything. I could use a log or...
我们需要一条船
What we really need is a boat.
谁又勃起了？
Who had dibs again?
快   跳进来
Come on, jump in.
这是地球上最好的登山向导   同感
-The best mountain guide on the planet. -Got that right.
你不会真以为我会自己逃跑吧？
You didn't really think you were gonna scare me away, did you?
我还没那么容易被吓倒
You'll have to work harder than that.
我想我得多收你一些额外的费用了
I'm afraid I'll have to charge you extra for this bit.
我能开个收据吗？ 哇
Can I open a tab? Whoa.
什么情况？
What was that?
真糟糕   这是河床
It's not good. That's the river bed.
水都蒸发掉了
We're running out of water.
各单位注意   抓稳了
Well, guys, you might wanna hang on to something.
这次的旅行可能会有点
This ride is about to get a little bit...
颠簸
Bumpy.
大家都没事吧？   嗯
-Is everybody all right?  Yeah.
我们在哪？
Where are we?
下面的光是什么？
What's that light down there?
那是熔岩
That's lava.
岩浆在不断升高
It's magma, and it's rising.
这条通道本来是有水的    水蒸气会向上喷射
There's supposed to be water in this tunnel. Steam, water shooting up.
我们太迟了   错过了喷泉
We're too late for the geyser, we missed it.
那怎么办？   你有没有什么办法 教授？
-What do we do? -Do you have any suggestions, professor?
没有水就没有蒸汽    没有蒸汽我们就哪也去不了
Without water, no steam. Without steam, we're not going anywhere.
这个地方好像已经两三个小时没有水经过了
This place looks like there hasn't been water here in two, three hours now.
但是墙壁还是湿的   不可能  现在已经一百三十度了
-But the walls are still wet. -That's impossible, it's 130 degrees.
崔佛   怎么了？   看你后面
-Trevor. Behind you. -What?
湿的
It is wet.
很冰凉   有水在后面
It's cold. There's water behind here.
一定是有暗流或者地下河
There's gotta be water behind some pocket or underground river.
崔佛  岩浆越来越近了
Trevor, it's getting closer.
这是镁
Hey, that's magnesium.
我们在下滑   你还有多少信号弹？
-We're slipping. -How many flares you got left?
三个   你想用来做什么？
Three. What do you wanna do with them?
我要点燃镁矿
Gonna light the magnesium. On purpose.
小心了
Hang on.
快着   太湿了
Oh, come on. It's too wet.
要往下一点   再给我一个
Got to get further down. Give me another one.
拉住我的腿
Hold my legs.
快着
Come on.
你们要绑住我   我要再往下面一点
You're gonna have to tie me off. I gotta get down lower.
崔佛  岩浆又近了
Trevor, it's getting closer.
那更好   来 准备
That's good. All right, ready.
最后一个
It's the last one.
小心啊 崔佛
Trevor, be careful.
怎样？   再下点
How's that?  Little more.
捉紧
Hurry.
还要低吗？   低一点
Lower?  Little more.
好   稳住
Okay, hold off.
拜托  拜托
-Come on.  Come on.
拜托  快点着   拜托
Come on, light.  Come on.
加油  崔佛
Come on, Trevor.
还是太湿   我要把它扔到对面
Still wet. Gonna have to throw it to the other side.
什么？
What?
别
No.
我去！
No!
崔佛  回来
Trevor, come on.
崔佛  回来   它着了  它点着了
-Trevor, come on. -It's lit, it's lit.
拉！
Pull!
拉我上去   快点
-Pull me up. -Hurry.
拉我上去   拉我上去
Pull me up. Pull me up.
快  拉起来    拉
Come on, pull it. Pull it.  Pull.
小心牙齿   小心牙齿
Watch the teeth. Watch the teeth.
小贤！快！
Sean! Come on!
趴下  它要爆炸了
Get down, it's gonna blow.
这东西在变热
This thing's heating up.
我知道！
I know!
抓稳！  我已经抓稳了！
-Hang on! -Trust me, I'm hanging on!
那是天空吗？
Is that sky?
大家都抓稳了！
Hang on, everybody!
你好吵啊！  我情不自禁就说出来了！
-Stop saying that! -It just keeps coming up!
那是维苏威火山
That's Mount Vesuvius.
小贤   如果你妈妈问起你这个周末去哪了
Hey, Sean, if your mom asks you what you did this weekend...
你就告诉她崔佛叔叔带你去意大利了    意大利？
...you tell her Uncle Trevor took you to Italy. -Italy?
小贤？
Sean?
怎么了？ 我不过是收集了一点点地质样本
What? I just took a few geological samples.
这叫一点点？
A few geological samples?
好吧  一堆样本   那有什么办法？  我可是科学家的后代啊
A few pounds of samples, but what do you expect? I'm a scientist's son.
看  看
Look. Look.
这个给你
You take this.
你拿   我们抱歉
You take. We are sorry.
你们要再滑一次吗？
You want slide again?
怎么滑都没问题
Slide is okay. It's fine.
你们想干嘛就干嘛
Anything what you want.
你这是为什么？
What was that for?
现在我们扯平了
Now we're even.
雷诺 我回来了    你不用找了
Leonard, I'm back. Stop doing what you're doing.
我没找什么啊？
What am I doing?
噢  看   你在找工作
Oh, look, you're looking for work.
没必要找了   因为你已经有工作了
You don't need to, because you have a job...
“格森-安德森”地质勘察协会
...with the Asgeirsson-Anderson Institute for Tectonophysical Exploration.
“格森-安德森”……  啥？
The Asgeirsson-Anderson... What?
名字其实还没想好
Still working on the name.
一人得道   鸡犬升天
But the point is, rising tide lifts all boats.
太好了
Man, that's awesome.
那个   我是那鸡犬吗？
I think... Am I a boat?
对 没错    我们可以继续搭档了    太好了
-You're a boat. We're back in business. -All right, dude.
喂 喂 喂    这么兴奋什么事情呢？
Well, well, well. What's all the excitement about?
嗨  艾伦  你好啊？  很好
-Oh, hey, Alan. How are you? Good.
你在干嘛？   我吗？
-What you doing? -Oh, me?
我准备搬进我的新实验室
I'm moving into my new lab.
话说回来   你去哪了？
More importantly, where have you been?
我听说你缺席了星期一的演讲   你的学生都在抱怨呢
I heard you missed your Monday lecture and both of your students complained.
哦！
Oh!
我去了趟旅行   毕生难忘
I took a quick vacation. Best thing I could've done.
那真是刺激
That is exciting.
找天跟我讲讲旅行的经过吧？
You'll have to promise to tell me about it, okay?
我可能没有空
但是你可以在《美国科学》上读一读我的论文
Not sure if I'll have time, but you can read about it in Scientific American.
《美国科学》？
Scientific American?
我只是希望  你不要太羡慕  好吗？
Look, I just want to say, no hard feelings, okay?
关于实验室搬迁以及其他杂物
About the laboratory moving and expansion thing.
我会去找一栋我自己的实验室的
So I'm actually looking for my own building anyway.
你想要怎么找一栋实验室呢？
How exactly are you going to do that, Trevor?
呃   你可以理解为我踩狗屎运了
Well, let's just say I fell into a small fortune.
明天你要去加拿大了？
So tomorrow you're gonna be a Canadian.
对   没错
Yep. Looks that way.
我觉得这次相聚太短暂了
I'd say that was a lot of male bonding packed into very little time.
下次我们一起玩几个星期  怎么样？
What do you say we take a couple weeks next time?
几个星期？
A couple weeks?
圣诞假期你有安排吗？   没有  我很闲
-What are you doing over Christmas break? -Nothing. I'm free.
我刚从你爸的东西里找到这个
I just found this in your dad's stuff.
读一下
Give it a read.
《迷失帝国-亚特兰蒂斯》？   嗯
-"Lost City of Atlantis."  Mm-hm.
再约吧
We'll talk.
小贤 那是什么？
Sean, what is that?
我在喂我的宠物   什么宠物？
-I'm just feeding my pet. -What pet?
小贤
Sean.
你觉得我妈妈会让我养他嘛？   我怎么知道
-You think my mom will let me keep him? -I don't know.
他肯不肯被养都成问题
Might not even stay here.
你看   嘿 回来
-Look at it. -Hey, come on.
这就是你的问题了    你要去哪？
-This is your problem. -Where are you going?
我这里有好吃的    回来   快下来
I got some food for you. Come on. Come back down here.
回来
Come on.
中文字幕翻译：梦海肥亮
30724623@qq.com